Obedientia. Paupertas.
The Little Hours is a comedy film directed by Jeff Baena.
Garfagnana, Italy, 1347.
The handsome servant Masseto, fleeing from his vindictive master, takes shelter in a nunnery where three young nuns, Sister Alessandra, Sister Ginevra
and Sister Fernanda, try unsuccessfully to find out what their purpose in life is, a conundrum that each of them faces in different ways.
Sister Alessandra, played by Alison Brie.
Masseto, played by Dave Franco.
Sister Ginevra, played by Kate Micucci.
Sister Fernanda, played by Aubrey Plaza.
Father Tommasso, played by John C. Reilly.
Sister Marea, played by Molly Shannon.
The Little Hours is a 2017 black comedy film written and directed by Jeff Baena and loosely based on stories
from the third day of The Decameron, a 14th-century collection of novellas by Giovanni Boccaccio.
It stars an ensemble cast featuring Alison Brie, Dave
Franco, Aubrey Plaza, Kate Micucci, John C.
Reilly, Molly Shannon, and Fred Armisen.
Set in the 14th century, The Little Hours uses modern dialogue – in the spirit of its
source material – improvised by the actors based on Baena's detailed outline.
It focuses on the sex lives of its characters, including nuns at a convent (Brie, Micucci, Plaza and Shannon) in rural Tuscany, a local coven of witches, and
a young servant (Franco) who ends up pretending to be a deaf-mute gardener at the convent after running away from his master (Nick Offerman).
It premiered at the Sundance Film Festival on January 19, 2017, and was theatrically released
by Gunpowder & Sky, the company's first such distribution, on June 30, 2017.
Muted complaints from Catholic groups did not negatively affect the film's release; it received
generally positive reviews from critics, featuring praise for the cast's performances.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, middle ages
(476-1453), convent (nunnery), nunhood, 14th century.
The tone is lighthearted.